RESUME

ROSHAN SHARMA

Email: rshn_shrm@yahoo.com

Contact: 98275-34813.

Key Skills

- Recruitment
- Talent Acquisition
- Client Acquisition
- HR Generalist
- Campus Hiring

PROFILE SNAPSHOT

As a Talent Acquisition recruiter with 5.6 years of experience, I am responsible for sourcing, attracting, interviewing, hiring, onboarding employees and manpower planning.

Industry Exposure: Retail, Pharma, Banking, Ecommerce, NBFC, BPO, IT.

Portals Used: Naukri.com, Linkedin.

Key Areas: Sourcing, Hiring, Staffing, Onboarding.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Present Organization	Corecard Software India Pvt Ltd, Bhopal (IT)
Designation	Talent Acquisition
From	Since March 2021

JOB PROFILE

About Company: Core Card Software is a product company, to provide financial service organizations with the best card management applications to help them compete both locally and globally. Core Card Software, a leading provider of card management systems

Primary Responsibilities:

- Responsible for end to end recruitment life cycle.
- Responsible for planning and executing the recruitment strategy to identify the potential needs and future hiring

Responsibilities:

- Coordinating with hiring managers to identify staffing needs and candidate selection criteria.
- Defining job positions, advertising vacancies, sourcing, screening, shortlisting, scheduling & assessment,
 shortlisting, Salary negotiation/ HR discussion, documentation & verification.
- Sourcing applicants through online channels, such as Naukri, LinkedIn and other professional networks.
- Compiling lists of most-suitable candidates by assessing their CVs, portfolios, and references.
- Devise and implement sourcing strategies to a strong candidate pipeline.
- Maintain records of all materials used for recruitment, including interview notes and related paperwork,
 to share with key stakeholders.

Previous Organization	Career Net Consulting ,Indore (Banking, BPO, NBFC, ecommerce, IT)
Designation	Associate Consultant
From	28 JAN 2016 to March 2018.

About Company: CareerNet is the leading provider of Talent Acquisition and Recruitment Process Outsourcing solutions to the Technology, Knowledge Services, Banking and Financial Services sectors in India.

Responsibilities:

- Was responsible for sourcing/screening/scheduling of candidates for our Clients.
- Good understanding of Client Requirements-Job Specifications, Job Description and Compensation Break
 up.
- Identifying target companies from where CVs should be preferably sourced.
- Short-listing the profiles from job portals and social networking sites.
- Coordinating with the client and candidates through the recruitment process till the candidate joins the company.

Recruitment for various IT Positions for the Junior and Senior Management Level.

Previous Organization	CIPLA LTD ,Indore (Pharma)
Designation	Assistant HR
From	17 FEB 2014 to 31 st May 2014.

JOB PROFILE

About Company: Cipla is a leading pharmaceutical from India with presence across the world. The company has a vast portfolio with more than 1,500 products in the market.

Responsibilities:

- Entire process of Recruitment & selection, Scrutinizing, Short listing of Candidates, Scheduling &
 Conducting Interviews & HR Round
- Assisting HR Head in the recruitment and selection procedure, arrangement of interview schedule.
 Maintaining the all details in recruitment drive.
- Expertise in complete recruitment life cycle, which includes identifying, sourcing, screening, negotiation, background verification, reference check and pre/post offer followup.
- Coordination with Performance Management System.
- Handling Joining Formalities Checking References, Scrutinizing Joining Documents, Medical

Previous Organization	Human Power Services ,Indore (Retail , Manufacturing)
Designation	Senior Recruitment Consultant
From	01 FEB 2011 to Dec 2011

JOB PROFILE

About Company: Human Power Services is a company committed to the advancement of HR solutions to growing companies. To-"Keep your dreams alive. Understand to achieve anything requires faith and belief in yourself, vision, hard work, determination, and dedication

Responsibilities:

- Receiving Requirement from Client
- Searching Relevant Profiles from our databank and job portals.
- Calling the Candidates to our office to conduct Pre-screening
- Scrutinizing the candidates on the basis of Pre-screening done
- Sending the Scrutinized Profiles to the Client for further short listing
- Arranging the interview
- Receiving status of the candidates from Client.

EDUCATIONALTERTIARY

- Master of Business Administration (HR & Marketing) at Indore Institute of science and technology, Devi Ahilya University. Indore in 2011
- Bachelor of Science at Govt Holkar Science College, Devi Ahilya University, Indore in 2007.
- 12th HSC at MP Board, Badnagar Ujjain in 2004.
- 10th SSC at MP Board, Badnagar, Ujjain in 2002.

PERSONAL DETAILS

DOB : 18/09/1985

Languages known: Hindi, English, Sindhi

Hobbies: Reading Motivational Books, Watching Motivational Videos.

Date:-

Place: - (ROSHAN SHARMA)